[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 13]
Who is it?
Shen Fuxuan, are you awake?
Yes.
Coming.
Morning.
Did you get this for me?
Thank you.
Well,
I got this last night
in case you got hungry.
Morning.
Why are you here?
Surprising, right?
You two wait here for a bit.
I'll go change my clothes,
and then we can go down
for breakfast together.
I don't think you should drink coffee
on an empty stomach.
I need to drink some.
I didn't dare to sleep last night,
so I'm afraid I'll get sleepy later.
Thanks to you,
I slept very well last night.
Thank you.
You didn't sleep well last night either?
I'm not used to unfamiliar beds.
It's time. I have to go.
I'll attend your presentation.
Really?
Of course.
It's such an important occasion.
How could I miss it?
See you later then.
See you later.
See you later, Shen Fuxuan.
[The 6th Nanhai Provincial Symposium
on Marine Science Development]
Okay, thank you.
Today,
we have a special segment.
We've invited a high school student
to interpret and discuss
marine issues from her perspective.
Please welcome
Lin Zhixia, a high school student
from Nanhai No. 1 High School.
A round of applause, please.
[The 6th Nanhai Provincial Symposium
on Marine Science Development]
Hello, everyone.
I'm the high school student
representative today, Lin Zhixia.
I was very nervous backstage just now.
Seeing so many outstanding experts
and scholars
engaging in in-depth discussions
made me, as a student, realize that
the academic path
is a long and arduous one.
Today I want to share with you
a topic that is closely related to us.
Don't take photos. You'll distract her.
What do you know?
I've turned off the flash.
I'm recording her highlight moment.
Point it up a bit.
It has already attracted
widespread attention.
But today I want to specifically
discuss microplastics.
There is currently
no unified definition of microplastics.
They generally refer to
plastic fragments at the millimeter
or even micrometer level.
Actually, this topic is quite advanced.
What.
What do you mean by that?
I'm afraid you won't understand it.
Actually, you can go home
and brush up on the basics.
Don't force yourself.
When have you scored better than me
on an exam this semester?
If anyone doesn't understand, it's you.
This is a Marine Science Seminar.
Have you forgotten who my mom is?
I've been immersed in it since childhood.
Even my bedtime stories
were about oceanography.
Thus, they enter the food chain.
This causes problems for the creatures,
including indigestion, energy deficiency,
injury, poisoning, and even death.
As we just mentioned,
microplastics enter the ocean
through various pathways.
Now let's see what those pathways are.
There are 4 main pathways of input.
Lifestyle pathway.
Our daily domestic wastewater
will all be discharged into the ocean.
Laundry wastewater...
[The Harm of Microplastics
to the Nanhai Ecosystem]
Fourth, and most importantly,
is to raise public awareness.
[Thanks]
Due to a lack of systematic study
in oceanography,
my research
remains at a relatively superficial stage.
I would like to express my special thanks
to Professor Shen Zhaohua's lab team
for their patient guidance.
With their help,
I was able to collect seawater samples
and offshore sediments
of Nanhai Province shores,
and more effectively observe
the distribution and
pollution status of microplastics.
I think in the next decade,
microplastics are very likely to become
one of the biggest challenges
in global ocean governance.
I hope the treatment
and prevention of microplastics
will become an issue that everyone
pays more attention to.
I also hope my sharing
can provide you with some new ideas.
That concludes my presentation for today.
Thank you all.
Later, make a copy of your slides today
for Ms. Guan.
Great. So excellent.
When she was still young,
I met her at the aquarium.
So she is really a gifted talent.
The reason I invited her
is that our team needs such a talent.
Xia, Ms. Guan here is
a prominent teacher in the field
with her own unique insights on the
future development of marine science.
I'm back.
Baihui, come here.
[Gentle Battle Hymn]
Explain this.
This... This...
I've noticed you haven't been as quick
to get up these past couple of days.
I thought you had
finally figured things out
and stayed up late studying.
Turns out you were reading this.
Where did this come from?
Did you buy it yourself?
No.
This...
[Gentle Battle Hymn]
This is just...
a gift from Lin Zhixia.
but I didn't read it.
A gift from Lin Zhixia?
Do ace students have time to read this?
They are all busy
doing practice questions.
She knows that for this exam,
your grades dropped so severely,
yet she still gave you this leisure book?
She is mocking you
for never being able to catch up to her!
Baihui, we wouldn't hurt you.
She has good grades.
She's pretending to be your good friend
to make you lower your guard.
And you actually took it seriously.
[Gentle Battle Hymn]
Go, return it to her today.
Dad, I swear I haven't read it.
I will never talk to her again.
As for this book,
can I just throw it away myself?
I'll pretend I never had it.
If you won't go, I will.
I will personally hand this book to her
and let her reflect on
her true intentions.
Mom, if I really do it,
-what will my classmates think of me?
-Is that important?
Classmates are just competitors.
When Lin Zhixia gave you the book,
she was probably mocking you in her heart.
Do you understand?
But Dad...
I'm not discussing this with you.
I got it.
You took photos?
Let me see.
Videos, too.
You took so many.
How did I do?
Good.
Really good.
What do you think of my research topic?
Good.
Very good.
A strawberry!
These are all your favorites.
We sat through a morning of reports.
Haven't you seen enough?
Eat something.
You must be hungry.
Eat up.
By the way.
My mom still has wrap-up work
this afternoon,
so we have free time.
Is there anything you want to do?
A sci-fi blockbuster
was released recently.
Let's go watch the movie.
Sure.
Where's my share?
Go help yourself.
[Currently Airing]
[Snacks Ordering]
Hello. How can I help you?
These badges are so beautiful.
These are badges
for the movie "Pale Blue Dot."
Our cinema is having
a promotion right now.
If you participate,
you can check in and get a badge.
What promotion?
Right here.
This is the promotion.
[Exclusive Benefit for Couples]
Couples can take a photo together
to get a limited-edition badge.
[Capture the moment of love]
This is the couples' photo check-in wall.
Non-couples should be fine too.
Why don't we take a photo together?
[Winter Snow]
We should be able to get the badge too.
Makes sense.
I don't think that's a good idea.
[Capture the moment of love]
What's wrong with it?
Please. Thank you.
You two, stand a little closer.
Strike a pose.
Let's do a peace sign.
I'm going to take the picture now.
Ready.
Three, two, one.
[Exclusively for couples]
Here is the photo of you two.
Please keep it safe.
This photo is really interesting.
Can I keep it?
I want this badge.
Here you go.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Row 5, seats 9, 10, and 11.
Right here.
I'll go in first.
Move inside.
It's been a long time
since I came to the cinema.
Shen Fuxuan.
Hold out your hand.
Both hands.
Both.
It's more convenient to hold it
and eat it yourself.
Is it enough?
Jin Baihui?
I'm Lin Zhixia's brother.
My name is Lin Zeqiu.
Hello.
How do you know who I am?
You are one of the top students
in my sister's class.
I know you.
And after the school anniversary,
who in the school doesn't know you?
Are you here to see my sister today?
I...
This...
Please give this to Lin Zhixia.
She's not at home. Maybe wait a bit?
We are all stardust.
Adrift in the same darkness.
Even when we're apart,
we are still under the same sky.
We don't own each other,
but we can light up
one another's darkness.
I'm going to the restroom.
Are you cold?
This is hot.
Hold it to warm up.
Thank you.
No problem.
You haven't been here, have you?
This is Lin Zhixia's and my secret base.
She loves drawing.
This is a drawing of our house
from when she was little.
She drew it in kindergarten.
No, in primary school.
That one over there
is from kindergarten.
And this one.
This was
also drawn in kindergarten.
Her drawings were cuter back then.
And these are from middle school.
These are less childish.
She said
I was that little frog,
and she'd be the umbrella to shelter me
when she grew up.
Give me a break.
Who knows who's protecting whom?
Look at this.
This is a seat from a minibus.
We snatched it from a junk collector.
It's actually broken.
See, it has no leg on that side.
See, we stacked bricks there
to keep it steady and functional.
Just like that.
Here, there are bricks here, too.
This one is broken too,
but it works with bricks under it.
My parents' supermarket had
old vegetable crates. We put them here,
threw a cloth over them,
and it became our space capsule.
As for this cloth...
I used it when I was little.
It was my blanket.
And there's more.
The navigator sits here,
and there's an accelerator inside.
It's nice having siblings.
It was all her idea.
I just did what she said.
But I like it here too.
Because here you can see
the whole sky.
That's the Winter Triangle.
Next to it is the Hexagon.
It's very visible.
Among them, Sirius, the closest one to us,
is slowly approaching us.
Are you interested in astronomy?
I'm the president of
the school's astronomy club.
Aren't you in any clubs?
No. I'm afraid it'll affect my studies.
Not really.
You just need to manage your time.
You can come check out
the astronomy club sometime.
Besides,
if you study all day,
won't you go crazy?
The movie was really good.
Pale Blue Dot.
The blue dot is our Earth.
Alone in the universe,
yet afraid of not being alone.
It really was good.
Were you actually paying attention?
Hello, Mom.
Okay.
Got it.
My mom is done over there.
I need to head over.
Do you want to...
Go ahead.
I'll take her home.
Alright then.
It's getting late.
It's not safe outside.
Go back and rest early.
Let's go.
Help me hold my bag.
Is this book...
Lin Zhixia gave this to me.
My parents found out.
They were afraid
it would affect my studies...
So they asked me to return it.
It's already torn like this.
Why didn't you just throw it
in a trash can by the road?
You're so honest,
so naive.
That's true.
Alright then, give it to me.
I'll handle it.
Just say you've already returned it.
Thank you.
I guess I'm already used to it.
I do whatever they tell me.
Please say sorry to Lin Zhixia for me.
She actually won't blame you.
My sister didn't have many friends
when she was little.
She was quite a misfit.
So my parents
were also very worried
about her making friends.
If they knew you were coming today,
they would have been very happy.
I...
I'm not sure if we're considered friends.
She gave you a book,
so you are definitely her friend.
I think Lin Zhixia
is genuinely nice to me,
but my parents always believe that
she is purposely distracting me
with singing and leisure books.
She's afraid I'd surpass her.
Your parents are overthinking.
That's impossible.
I'm not saying it's impossible
for you to surpass her.
I mean...
In this regard, my sister...
Her brain, you know,
is just a bit abnormal.
But when she gave you the book,
it must have been sincere.
When I was a kid, I loved watching
the stars with my brother the most.
Jiang Yubai, look.
There are so many stars
in the sky tonight.
Yeah.
Are you also looking at Sirius?
How did you know?
Because the aliens in the movie
were from Sirius.
If you were given a chance
to explore outer space for aliens,
but you probably wouldn't be
able to come back,
would you go?
In life,
people are naturally curious.
We all want to see
what the universe looks like.
But if I couldn't come back,
I'd probably have too many
emotional ties I can't let go of.
I would go.
Even if you can't come back?
I don't need to come back.
Once I find a new home,
all humanity can just move over.
Then you...
I'm not cold.
Did you know?
Sirius is actually 8.6 light-years
away from us.
Because its brightness
is 25 times that of the Sun,
we can see it
from so far away.
This beam of light
took 8.6 years to reach Earth.
That means before we even met,
it had already embarked
on the journey to meet us.
How romantic.
Since
it had such a hard time getting here,
shall we take a photo with it
as a souvenir?
Sure.
It's right here.
Ready, 3, 2, 1.
It's a bit crooked.
Let's take another one.
Three, two, one.
It's a bit blurry and out of focus.
Let's take another one.
Three, two, one.
[Happiness is so simple]
This one is a bit out of focus.
Let's take another one.
Three.
The bus is here.
Many of the photos we just took
are out of focus.
Should we retake...
♪ The moment our eyes met,
my world came alive with color ♪
♪ Could this be how love begins? ♪
♪ These unspoken feelings
are so hard to figure out ♪
♪ Hidden deep within your gaze ♪
♪ Sometimes, I imagine
drifting beyond the skies with you ♪
♪ Shimmering light
dances over the flower in bloom ♪
♪ After all we've been through,
our fates remain intertwined ♪
♪ Perhaps fate favors me now ♪
Thank you, Jiang Yubai.
I'm home.
Then...
See you at school next week.
Here you go.
Good night, Jiang Yubai.
Good night, Lin Zhixia.
Lin Zhixia!
Come here!
What's wrong?
Where did you go?
I...
I called your hotel twice.
They said you checked out this afternoon.
Where did you go?
Why are you back so late?
If you were 10 minutes later,
I would have called the police!
The seminar was in the suburbs.
It takes time for me to get back.
You knew it would take time,
so why didn't you call home?
How could I call
when I don't even have a phone?
Well...
Then you need to get a phone.
Mom, Dad, you're back.
You...
Why aren't you asleep yet?
What are you two up to?
We were waiting for you to come back.
Is something wrong?
Just drop it.
No.
I have to bring this up.
What is it?
I think Lin Zhixia needs a phone.
Because she is a girl,
it's not safe for her to be out alone.
So she needs a phone.
All her classmates have phones too.
She looks out of place without one.
Therefore, she needs a phone.
Oh, about that.
Actually,
your mom and I
have already discussed this.
The New Year is coming soon.
Recently, the supermarket
has stocked up on New Year goods.
We were planning to buy you
each a phone after
the New Year.
Yes.
Dad, I don't need a phone right now.
But please get one for Lin Zhixia first.
And the sooner, the better.
[The 6th Nanhai Provincial Symposium
on Marine Science Development]
Why is it so blurry?
It's all out of focus.
Should we retake...